A Guide to the Gordon Thomas Whyburn Papers, 1926-1929
Gordon Thomas Whyburn Papers
1926-1929
Whyburn, Gordon Thomas, 1904-
98-082
1 inch
Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, The University of Texas at Austin
The Whyburn (Gordon Thomas) Papers consist of 17 off-prints (bound copies of articles published in journals) of Whyburn's contributions to scientific and mathematical journals between 1926 and 1929.
Biographical Note
Gordon Thomas Whyburn (1904-1969) attended the University of Texas at Austin, obtaining Bachelors and Masters Degrees from the Department of Chemistry. He earned his Ph. D. in Mathematics in 1927 and became adjunct professor of mathematics from 1927 to 1929. Whyburn studied in Europe with Hans Hahn, Kazimerz Kuratowski, and Waclaw Sierpinski before being appointed associate professor of mathematics at Johns Hopkins University in 1930. In 1934, he accepted appointment as professor and chairman of the Department of Mathematics at the University of Virginia, where he stayed for the remainder of his career. He researched topology, cyclic elements, the structure of continua, homology theory, and examined different notions of convergents in the space of all subsets of a compact metric space.
Scope and Contents
The Whyburn (Gordon Thomas) Papers consist of 17 off-prints (bound copies of articles published in journals) of Whyburn's contributions to scientific and mathematical journals between 1926 and 1929.
Forms part of the Archives of American Mathematics
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted access
Index Terms
Subjects
Whyburn, Gordon Thomas, 1904-; University of Texas at Austin. Dept. of Mathematics; Continuum (mathematics); Convergence; Homology Theory; Mathematics - Periodicals; Mathematics - Study and teaching - United States; Topology
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Literary productions of Gordon T. Whyburn:
  - "Two-Way Continuous Curves," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, November-December, 1926. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning Certain Types of Continuous Curves," Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, vol. 12, no. 12, December 1926. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Cyclicly Connected Continuous Curves," Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, vol. 13, no. 2, February 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "The Most General Closed Point Set Over Which Continuous Function May be Defined By Certain Properties," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, March-April 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning Continua in the Plane" (Doctoral Dissertation), Transactions of the American Mathematical Society, vol. 29, no. 2, April 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Some Properties of Continuous Curves," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, May-June 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning the Open Subsets of a Plane Continuous Curve," Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, vol. 13, no. 9, September 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning Point Sets Which Can Be Made Connected by the Addition of a Simple Continuous Arc," Transactions of the American Mathematical Society, vol. 29, no. 4, October 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning Regular and Connected Point Sets," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, November-December 1927. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "On Continuous Curves in n Dimensions," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, May-June 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning the Structure of a Continuous Curve," American Journal of Mathematics, vol. 50, no.2, April 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning the Cut Points of Continua," Transactions of the American Mathematical Society, vol. 30, no. 3, July 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning the Complementary Domains of Continua," Annals of Mathematics, vol. 29, no.4, November 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "On Certain Accessible Points of Plane Continua," Monatshefte fur Mathematik und Physik, vol.35, 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "On a Problem of W. L. Ayres," Fundamenta Mathematicae, vol. 11, 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "Concerning Menger Regular Curves," Fundamenta Mathematicae, vol. 12, 1928. (Box 2.325/A101)
  - "On Regular Points of Continua and Regular Curves of at Most Order n," Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society, March-April 1929. (Box 2.325/A101)